Shinji Pons, Senior Product Designer

Toulouse, France +33 07 44 74 31 34 hello@shinjipons.com

Links Portfolio https://shinjipons.com

Linkedin https://linkedin.com/in/shinjipons/

Github https://github.com/shinjipons/

Layers https://layers.to/shinjipons

Summary

I'm a results-driven product designer with 10 years of experience designing complex desktop software applications for creative professionals in the automotive, video game and animation industries.

Areas of Expertise

Product Design

Figma

Python

UI/UX Design

Blender

JavaScript

Wireframing

Autodesk Alias

HTML/CSS

Prototyping 3D Modelling

Employment History

Jun 2023 - May 2024

Senior Product Designer at Ragdoll Dynamics

Toulouse, France

- Sole designer at an early-stage company revolutionizing 3D character animation through rigid body simulation.
- Designed a new standalone desktop application and created a comprehensive design system from the ground up.
- · Contributed to the testing and release of the Ragdoll Dynamics for Blender add-on.
- · Prototyped interface elements using ImGui integrated via JavaScript.
- Improved customer processes by adopting Attio, enhancing communication and customer relationship management.

Jan 2021 - May 2023

Senior Experience Designer at Electronic Arts

Guildford, United Kingdom

- Enhanced tools and workflows for over 5000 professionals using Frostbite, EA's proprietary game engine.
- Shaped future character creation workflows for AAA titles including Skate, EA FC, and UFC.
- Focused on character workflows for EA Sports & Racing titles, optimizing runtime deformation and mass loading of character assets.

May 2019 - Dec 2021

Senior Product Designer at The LEGO Group

Billund, Denmark

- · Modernized LEGO Digital Designer Pro, the in-house 3D CAD-like modeller.
- Led design experience leveraging brick data for improved connectivity, pricing, and collision detection.
- Reduced repetitive task time by up to 90% through redesigning essential tools.
- Built a fully digital pipeline from concept to marketing for 70% of new LEGO products.

Employment History (continued)		
Jun 2017 - May 2019	Experience Designer at Autodesk	Hanover, Germany
	 Directed design for fast concept modelling and computational design in Alias, the leading 3D CAD software. Led design of subdivision modelling features in Alias 2020. Conducted user testing workshops with over 60 professional users from top automotive studios like Volvo and Toyota. Delivered tools that sped up concept design finalization by 60%. 	
Apr 2016 - Apr 2017	Experience Designer at Thomson Reuters	London, United Kingdom
	 Designed prototypes and features using natural language processing to automate risk detection in the World-Check Risk Intelligence product. 	
Feb 2015 - Nov 2015	User Experience Designer at Microsoft	London, United Kingdom
	 Created interactive experiences in public spaces to raise awareness of the Windows Devices brand. 	
Dec 2014 - Feb 2015	 User Interface Designer at Style.com Designed branding and user interface elements for a fashion, travel, and luxury content and e-commerce platform. 	
Education		
2010 - 2014	London College of Communication	London, United Kingdom
	Bachelor of Arts, Graphic & Media Design (First Class Honours)	
Languages	French Native speaker	
	English Native speaker	
Internships		
Sep 2014 - Dec 2014	Graphic Design Intern at Barnbrook	London, United Kingdom
	• Designed, laid out, and art-worked for clients including Art Basel and David Bowie.	
Oct 2012 - Jan 2013	Graphic Design Intern at Ateliers Jean Nouvel	Paris, France
	Designed icon and typographic signage systems for the Louvre Abu Dhabi (in French, English, and Arabic)	

English, and Arabic).